<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>mf://TODO by Michael Forrest</title>
		<description>Michael Forrest's Museum of Unfinished Projects</description>
		<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://michaelforrest.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>3. The Fifth Theory</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is an autobiographical, philosophical comic I started a few years ago. everything is hand drawn on paper in a linear process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed creating something physical after years of doing everything on computers. The lack of &lt;em&gt;undo&lt;/em&gt; leads to a very different sort of creative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='whats_it_about'&gt;What&amp;#8217;s it about?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of it, I&amp;#8217;d have admit, is me airing some emotional laundry. In some ways my entry into the world could have been easier. The narrative charts my progress from strong religious beliefs, through a faith in science and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Prologue' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/prologue.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='Title Page' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/title_page.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='Hats' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/hats.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='The Switch' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/switch.jpeg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title refers to an idea I arrived at in my early twenties. I studied Physics at University and everything ultimately comes down to four forces of nature: gravitation, the electromagnetic force, the weak nuclear force and the strong nuclear force. My theory is that the fifth force of nature, a force which binds and drives new kinds of creation and interaction between elements in the universe, emerges from a property of the amalgamation of the other forces into ordered patterns, code, behaviours - and ultimately - life. When life evolves to intelligence and society, this fifth force emerges, a force which allows the impossible to happen and intelligent beings to cooperate with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fifth theory is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; - without trust there would only be destruction. Trust lets us take for granted the intentions of our collaborators and move forward. Without trust we would be paralysed by uncertainty - never able to truly know the thoughts and motivations of others - we would be forced to remain separate, self sufficient, impoverished, aggressive; each one of us alone. We wouldn&amp;#8217;t last very long. Trust is a force which lets us act. For various reasons I grew up finding it difficult to trust anybody, so this conclusion is of no mean personal significance. I had to learn how to take people on their word and only by understanding this necessity as a force of nature was I able to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was writing this story as I joined the Ubuntu Design Team at &lt;em&gt;Canonical&lt;/em&gt;. I guess my day job just got too intense for me to find time to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve changed in significant ways since I started writing this story. I don&amp;#8217;t think I could resume it in its current form. I made a little iPhone app to distribute the story as a series but never got around to publishing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I made it means I&amp;#8217;m reluctant to take it apart and restructure it digitally. But I could remove a couple of pages instead. I suppose it could still be brought back to life as an online serial. I have no plans to do this though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that my earlier &lt;em&gt;finished&lt;/em&gt; comic &lt;em&gt;What Art Is, To Me&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href='http://grimaceworks.com/comics/what_art_is_to_me'&gt;available to read here&lt;/a&gt; and also available as &lt;a href='
https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/what-art-is-to-me/id322851225?mt=8'&gt;the first iPhone App I made&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/18/the-fifth-theory.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/18/the-fifth-theory.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2. Live DJ Concept</title>
				<description>&lt;h3 id='what_is_it'&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to define a new category of live performance between a band and a DJ. This category would be constituted like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usually a single performer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;live construction of music using loops and drum machines in combination with real instruments and singing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;performances would be dance-floor-friendly, minimising interruptions and pauses to keep people dancing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;music would generally be original based on the performer&amp;#8217;s repertoire of sounds, lyrics and techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this video with the idea of establishing this category as a new meme. The music is supposed to show the interesting genre mixing that happens when tempo-locked loops from different sources are layered up together, something I considered would be a recurring theme in my imagined Live DJ scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some footage of my own Live DJ skills&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class='youtube' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/-d2Zbowo3aU'&gt;  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a lot of artwork and didn&amp;#8217;t really like the style I was creating myself. I got quite impatient with After Effects and started wishing I had a more powerful computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, I just felt the concept was a bit cheesy, or maybe wasn&amp;#8217;t for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My real motivation for this project was to get some gigs. I ended up starting my own night &lt;a href='http://goodtohear.co.uk/squares'&gt;Squares&lt;/a&gt; and booking other acts to play alongside instead of pursuing the unrewarding process of emailing promoters asking for gigs (and never getting a response).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been to Ibiza since doing this, which I found quite instructive in understanding people&amp;#8217;s dancefloor expectations where DJs are involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anybody finds this blog post inspiring, sure. I&amp;#8217;m happy to share assets or get involved in any other way if anybody else thinks this concept, or something similar, has legs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/11/live-dj-concept.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/11/live-dj-concept.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>1. The Dubstep Machine</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Here is something I started a couple of years ago when dubstep still seemed quite cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was searching for the secret to making those types of musical progressions and came up with this app for interactively toggling and tuning tempo-locked loops. The visual aspect was important to me - I wanted to make sure there was always accurate graphical feedback tightly synchronised to the sound a la &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/TIS8YWfUvB8'&gt;Teenage Engineering OP-1&lt;/a&gt;. I built this prototype in about a day but then I stalled…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphic design&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;some decent loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;#8217;d decided to devote the bulk of my time to completing my &lt;a href='http://goodtohear.co.uk/happiness'&gt;Happiness Mood Tracking Journal App&lt;/a&gt; and this app didn&amp;#8217;t really in with the &amp;#8216;Apps For Life&amp;#8217; brand I was developing for &lt;em&gt;Good To Hear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I subsequently finished my &amp;#8216;dubstep anthem&amp;#8217; &lt;em&gt;Believe It&lt;/em&gt; so I do have some decent loops for it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder='no' height='166' scrolling='no' src='https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F33381290' width='100%'&gt;&lt;!-- KEEP --&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some ideas about the graphic design style too - I&amp;#8217;d like to see a grungy pixel art aesthetic referencing areas of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered this Mac App &lt;a href='http://www.paintcodeapp.com/'&gt;PaintCode&lt;/a&gt; that would be a good place to figure out some nice dynamic rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably. I might rebrand it &lt;em&gt;Death To Dubstep&lt;/em&gt; or something like that - &amp;#8220;the last nail in dubstep&amp;#8217;s coffin&amp;#8221; to make it seem less dated. But it&amp;#8217;s a very low priority at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='is_there_any_way_to_help'&gt;Is there any way to help?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dunno. If you&amp;#8217;re good at music visualisation or iOS programming you could help me get this finished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/04/dubstep-machine.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/04/dubstep-machine.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
