<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>mf://TODO by Michael Forrest</title>
		<description>Michael Forrest's Museum of Unfinished Projects</description>
		<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://michaelforrest.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>5. Done Good</title>
				<description>&lt;h3 id='what_is_it'&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June last year I decided it was time to make &lt;em&gt;Good To Hear&lt;/em&gt; next product, learning from what I&amp;#8217;d discovered while working on &lt;a href='http://goodtohear.co.uk/happiness'&gt;Happiness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d been using &lt;em&gt;Happiness&lt;/em&gt; and its antecedents for a few years and knew I had something that was capable of preventing depression but wasn&amp;#8217;t necessarily capable of making people happy. I wanted to find a way to help people be happy. Through software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer was something I&amp;#8217;d arrived at via a number of routes. There are a lot of things we can&amp;#8217;t control but the one guaranteed way to make onesself happy is to put other people first. Altruism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could I make to encourage people to help each other?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='how_to_make_something_viral'&gt;How to make something viral&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d recently observed something I&amp;#8217;d made going viral (the &amp;#8216;dickheadometer&amp;#8217; - a quiz that tells you how much of a hipster you are - hitting 50,000 views in under a week). Here are some things I was looking for to bring similar success to the next thing I made. I needed something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Shareable&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Where people who are not doing it should feel like they are missing out&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Collectable&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Creating some kind of social obligation&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Socially validating&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Including some sort of monetisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also knew I&amp;#8217;d need to start with a web app rather than an iPhone app this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='karma_bank'&gt;Karma Bank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could cover all these bases with the idea of a &amp;#8216;karma bank&amp;#8217;. A social network where you are seen helping people (and seen &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; helping people). Competitive altruism combining the encouragment of the happiness you get from helping someone else, with some guilt-tripping on the other side. &amp;#8220;Michael has not helped anyone for 8 days&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a system for keeping score. A &lt;em&gt;Runkeeper&lt;/em&gt; for selfless acts. I wanted to make this part of people&amp;#8217;s routine, and I could see the world becoming a much better place for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people might say &amp;#8220;if you only helped someone to grow your karma bank balance then it doesn&amp;#8217;t count&amp;#8221;. I couldn&amp;#8217;t disagree more. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter why you help someone, it only matters that you help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='the_first_wireframes'&gt;The first wireframes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out with a strong idea for a structure, including monetisation angles (via &amp;#8216;promoted&amp;#8217; deeds - because a company doing good is just as valid as an individual doing good). Click on the thumbnails below to see my second draft wireframes. (Use your arrow keys to zip left and right. If you&amp;#8217;re on a tablet the arrows appear when you sort of tap the right edge for now&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class='gallery thumbnails'&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/1.-Sign-in.png' title='1.-Sign-in'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/1.-Sign-in.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/2.-Profile.png' title='2.-Profile'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/2.-Profile.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/3.-Profile.png' title='3.-Profile'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/3.-Profile.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/4.-Good-deed-detail.png' title='4.-Good-deed-detail'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/4.-Good-deed-detail.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/5.-Good-deed-feed.png' title='5.-Good-deed-feed'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/5.-Good-deed-feed.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/5.-Settings.png' title='5.-Settings'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/5.-Settings.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/5.1-Invite-by-email.png' title='5.1-Invite-by-email'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/5.1-Invite-by-email.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/5.2-Invite.png' title='5.2-Invite'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/5.2-Invite.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/6.-New-deed.png' title='6.-New-deed'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/6.-New-deed.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/7.-Paid-good-deeds.png' title='7.-Paid-good-deeds'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/7.-Paid-good-deeds.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/7.1-Card-details.png' title='7.1-Card-details'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/7.1-Card-details.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/8.-API-documentation.png' title='8.-API-documentation'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/8.-API-documentation.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/8.1.-Badges.png' title='8.1.-Badges'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/8.1.-Badges.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/9.-Facebook-integration.png' title='9.-Facebook-integration'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/9.-Facebook-integration.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/9.-Web-home.png' title='9.-Web-home'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/9.-Web-home.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/karma_bank/9.1-Good-deed-landing-page.png' title='9.1-Good-deed-landing-page'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/karma_bank/9.1-Good-deed-landing-page.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt that a literal numerical score for your &amp;#8216;bank balance&amp;#8217; would be too easily gamed and was not entirely in the desired altruistic spirit. I wanted to find a softer way to keep score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t want to be working all on my own this time so I assembled a room full of creative and technical people, bought them some drinks, and we brainstormed ideas around my concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One breakthrough idea was to use the idea of climbing a ladder and being able to see others&amp;#8217; progress as they climbed their own, with all sorts of other things happening up in the sky. It might have been like &lt;em&gt;Tiny Tower&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='the_done_good_tree'&gt;The Done Good Tree&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='First Tree Sketch' src='/images/donegood/first_tree_sketch.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get away from any possible religious connotations with the name, so Karma Bank was never meant to stay. &lt;a href='http://matthewkempton.co.uk/' target='_blank'&gt;Matt Kempton&lt;/a&gt; came through with the name &amp;#8220;Done Good&amp;#8221; which perfectly hit the tone I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realised that a &lt;em&gt;tree&lt;/em&gt; was my ideal metaphor for the concept. Good deeds could grow branches, commentary could grow leaves, likes could grow fruit. A bragger would have a thicket of brown branches, others would have a healthy green orchard. People who were really trying would have a tree adorned with different kinds of colourful fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='graphic_design'&gt;Graphic design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stole some time here and there to get some help from Matt and others to figure out an appealing graphic design style for the site. I ended up settling on a sort of vibrant pixel art style, particularly inspired by the artwork in &lt;a href='http://polytroncorporation.com/what-is-fez'&gt;Fez&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site needed to work well on mobile so all the layouts needed to adapt to small screen sizes. You can see some of the screens I started with below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class='gallery thumbnails'&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/donegood_designs/1. Feed.png' title='1. Feed'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/donegood_designs/1. Feed.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/donegood_designs/2. Profile.png' title='2. Profile'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/donegood_designs/2. Profile.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/donegood_designs/3. Tree stages.png' title='3. Tree stages'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/donegood_designs/3. Tree stages.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/donegood_designs/4. Technical Sketch.png' title='4. Technical Sketch'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/donegood_designs/4. Technical Sketch.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class='thumbnail'&gt;&lt;a href='/images/donegood_designs/5. Technical Sketch.png' title='5. Technical Sketch'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/donegood_designs/5. Technical Sketch.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m working alone I don&amp;#8217;t usually spend longer than I have to in Photoshop. At a certain point it becomes quicker to experiment with HTML and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='development'&gt;Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I held out longer than I usually do before writing any code, but eventually it was time to bite the bullet. I was enamoured with &lt;a href='http://meteor.com'&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt; (and still am) so even though certain features of that particular framework were still a long way off, I knew that I&amp;#8217;d be able to get something up and running with the minimum of code if I used this platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was quite complex to test since it was so social. I was working with various fake Facebook users (as you can see by the video demo) to ensure that stories came through to people&amp;#8217;s feeds appropriately. All comments and likes on Facebook propagated to the feed in the Done Good app and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='so_what_happened'&gt;So what happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the site to a certain point but then I ran out of money and had to take on freelance work. I didn&amp;#8217;t want to release anything if I didn&amp;#8217;t have time to support it, and for a few months I was too busy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the site lives in a sort of nearly-finished form, with just enough usability problems that I&amp;#8217;m reluctant to share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_happened_since_then'&gt;Has anything happened since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended a &amp;#8221;&lt;a href='http://happathon.com/'&gt;H(app)athon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; and found myself facilitating a brainstorm on the subject of improving happiness. We all seemed to latch onto the idea of competitive altruism but here we framed it more as a process of &lt;em&gt;thanking&lt;/em&gt; than bragging. &lt;a href='http://arincrumley.wordpress.com/'&gt;Arin Crumley&lt;/a&gt; came up with the name &amp;#8220;Thank Bank&amp;#8221; and we pitched this concept to a room full of people and the consensus was that is was a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of us have stayed in touch and we had some ideas about pursuing this, although there are other similar projects emerging, such as &lt;a href='http://impossible.com'&gt;Impossible&lt;/a&gt;, something Jimmy Wales of Wikipedia fame has been involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to revisit this app, I&amp;#8217;d remove the ability to share your own good deeds in favour of making it a platform where people could thank each other. I think the &lt;em&gt;Thank Bank&lt;/em&gt; is a much better way of looking at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d really like to see this thing exist, but it might be a few years before I come back to it. Currently my priorities are elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll say this though: ever since I came up with this idea I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to prioritise helping others over helping myself whereever I can. I have found myself leading a much happier life as a result.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/10/04/donegood.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/10/04/donegood.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>4. Dinosaurs App</title>
				<description>&lt;h3 id='what_is_it'&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was going to be an iPhone app for kids. I started it after I&amp;#8217;d made some progress on my &amp;#8220;PuppetGraphics&amp;#8221; inverse kinematics library for iOS after a friend suggested my drawing style might be suitable for a kids&amp;#8217; book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some videos that show the asset preparation process so you can get more of an idea of how much technology went into achieving this innocuous little app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making something like this doesn&amp;#8217;t just involve a lot of programming the app itself - it needed additional tools to be programmed to get the graphics into a usable format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='analogue_phase'&gt;Analogue phase:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe class='youtube' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/_x8ISZf1OO4'&gt;  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id='digital_phase'&gt;Digital phase:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe class='youtube' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/dDCY0hwhlQg'&gt;  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was challenging on a technical and artistic level and I just never really found the time to solve the issues. I had some maths to work out for the animation engine, and the whole thing was built using low-level OpenGL apis rather than nice friendly UIView / CALayer apis (which I now regret). And then I failed to find time to finish all the artwork. I need backgrounds you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve written a lot more iOS apps so I have a much deeper understanding of all the performance tradeoffs of using different APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father (Richard Forrest of &lt;a href='http://plesiousaur.com'&gt;plesiosaur.com&lt;/a&gt;) showed me the beautiful paleo-art of &lt;a href='http://johnconway.co'&gt;John Conway&lt;/a&gt; which puts my illustrations to shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s no reason why I couldn&amp;#8217;t spend a few days finishing this off. It&amp;#8217;s just a matter of priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/25/dinosaurs-app.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/25/dinosaurs-app.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>3. The Fifth Theory</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This is an autobiographical, philosophical comic I started a few years ago. everything is hand drawn on paper in a linear process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed creating something physical after years of doing everything on computers. The lack of &lt;em&gt;undo&lt;/em&gt; leads to a very different sort of creative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='whats_it_about'&gt;What&amp;#8217;s it about?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of it, I&amp;#8217;d have admit, is me airing some emotional laundry. In some ways my entry into the world could have been easier. The narrative charts my progress from strong religious beliefs, through a faith in science and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Prologue' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/prologue.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='Title Page' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/title_page.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='Hats' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/hats.jpeg' /&gt; &lt;img alt='The Switch' src='/images/the_fifth_theory/switch.jpeg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title refers to an idea I arrived at in my early twenties. I studied Physics at University and everything ultimately comes down to four forces of nature: gravitation, the electromagnetic force, the weak nuclear force and the strong nuclear force. My theory is that the fifth force of nature, a force which binds and drives new kinds of creation and interaction between elements in the universe, emerges from a property of the amalgamation of the other forces into ordered patterns, code, behaviours - and ultimately - life. When life evolves to intelligence and society, this fifth force emerges, a force which allows the impossible to happen and intelligent beings to cooperate with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fifth theory is &lt;em&gt;trust&lt;/em&gt; - without trust there would only be destruction. Trust lets us take for granted the intentions of our collaborators and move forward. Without trust we would be paralysed by uncertainty - never able to truly know the thoughts and motivations of others - we would be forced to remain separate, self sufficient, impoverished, aggressive; each one of us alone. We wouldn&amp;#8217;t last very long. Trust is a force which lets us act. For various reasons I grew up finding it difficult to trust anybody, so this conclusion is of no mean personal significance. I had to learn how to take people on their word and only by understanding this necessity as a force of nature was I able to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was writing this story as I joined the Ubuntu Design Team at &lt;em&gt;Canonical&lt;/em&gt;. I guess my day job just got too intense for me to find time to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve changed in significant ways since I started writing this story. I don&amp;#8217;t think I could resume it in its current form. I made a little iPhone app to distribute the story as a series but never got around to publishing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I made it means I&amp;#8217;m reluctant to take it apart and restructure it digitally. But I could remove a couple of pages instead. I suppose it could still be brought back to life as an online serial. I have no plans to do this though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that my earlier &lt;em&gt;finished&lt;/em&gt; comic &lt;em&gt;What Art Is, To Me&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href='http://grimaceworks.com/comics/what_art_is_to_me'&gt;available to read here&lt;/a&gt; and also available as &lt;a href='
https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/what-art-is-to-me/id322851225?mt=8'&gt;the first iPhone App I made&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/18/the-fifth-theory.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/18/the-fifth-theory.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2. Live DJ Concept</title>
				<description>&lt;h3 id='what_is_it'&gt;What is it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to define a new category of live performance between a band and a DJ. This category would be constituted like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usually a single performer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;live construction of music using loops and drum machines in combination with real instruments and singing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;performances would be dance-floor-friendly, minimising interruptions and pauses to keep people dancing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;music would generally be original based on the performer&amp;#8217;s repertoire of sounds, lyrics and techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this video with the idea of establishing this category as a new meme. The music is supposed to show the interesting genre mixing that happens when tempo-locked loops from different sources are layered up together, something I considered would be a recurring theme in my imagined Live DJ scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some footage of my own Live DJ skills&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class='youtube' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/-d2Zbowo3aU'&gt;  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a lot of artwork and didn&amp;#8217;t really like the style I was creating myself. I got quite impatient with After Effects and started wishing I had a more powerful computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, I just felt the concept was a bit cheesy, or maybe wasn&amp;#8217;t for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My real motivation for this project was to get some gigs. I ended up starting my own night &lt;a href='http://goodtohear.co.uk/squares'&gt;Squares&lt;/a&gt; and booking other acts to play alongside instead of pursuing the unrewarding process of emailing promoters asking for gigs (and never getting a response).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been to Ibiza since doing this, which I found quite instructive in understanding people&amp;#8217;s dancefloor expectations where DJs are involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anybody finds this blog post inspiring, sure. I&amp;#8217;m happy to share assets or get involved in any other way if anybody else thinks this concept, or something similar, has legs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/11/live-dj-concept.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/11/live-dj-concept.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>1. The Dubstep Machine</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Here is something I started a couple of years ago when dubstep still seemed quite cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was searching for the secret to making those types of musical progressions and came up with this app for interactively toggling and tuning tempo-locked loops. The visual aspect was important to me - I wanted to make sure there was always accurate graphical feedback tightly synchronised to the sound a la &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/TIS8YWfUvB8'&gt;Teenage Engineering OP-1&lt;/a&gt;. I built this prototype in about a day but then I stalled…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='what_happened'&gt;What happened?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;graphic design&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;some decent loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;#8217;d decided to devote the bulk of my time to completing my &lt;a href='http://goodtohear.co.uk/happiness'&gt;Happiness Mood Tracking Journal App&lt;/a&gt; and this app didn&amp;#8217;t really in with the &amp;#8216;Apps For Life&amp;#8217; brand I was developing for &lt;em&gt;Good To Hear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='has_anything_changed_since_then'&gt;Has anything changed since then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I subsequently finished my &amp;#8216;dubstep anthem&amp;#8217; &lt;em&gt;Believe It&lt;/em&gt; so I do have some decent loops for it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder='no' height='166' scrolling='no' src='https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F33381290' width='100%'&gt;&lt;!-- KEEP --&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some ideas about the graphic design style too - I&amp;#8217;d like to see a grungy pixel art aesthetic referencing areas of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered this Mac App &lt;a href='http://www.paintcodeapp.com/'&gt;PaintCode&lt;/a&gt; that would be a good place to figure out some nice dynamic rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_it_be_revived'&gt;Can it be revived?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably. I might rebrand it &lt;em&gt;Death To Dubstep&lt;/em&gt; or something like that - &amp;#8220;the last nail in dubstep&amp;#8217;s coffin&amp;#8221; to make it seem less dated. But it&amp;#8217;s a very low priority at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='is_there_any_way_to_help'&gt;Is there any way to help?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dunno. If you&amp;#8217;re good at music visualisation or iOS programming you could help me get this finished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/04/dubstep-machine.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://michaelforrest.github.io/2013/09/04/dubstep-machine.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
